Inventory of the Thomas Byrne Edsall papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- William Donald Schaefer--Clipping, 1971, and notebooks, undated (Box-folder 20: 12)
- Memoranda, New York Times, undated (Box-folder 20: 13)
- Stuart Taylor--Memorandum, undated (Box-folder 20: 14)
- Copies of articles and notes for The Evening Sun, undated (Box-folder 20: 15)
- "Business Learns to Play New Politics," The Sun, undated
- 1 compact sound cassette, undated (Box 20)
- "Reform and the 95th Congress" (Box 21)
  - Typescript, 1977 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Data, 1977 (Box-folder 21: 2)
- "Tip On a Tightrope," James Barron and Marjorie Arons, Boston Phoenix, 1976 December 7 (Box-folder 21: 3)
- Purchasing real estate, 1980 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  Includes offer to purchase and standard sale agreement
- Developers-–Building permits and related materials, 1972 (Box-folder 21: 5)
- Correspondence, minutes of meetings, and petition of appeal involving a court case relating to the denial by the city agencies to grant building permits to private housing developers, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 21: 6)
- Correspondence with Venable, Baetjer, and Howard, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 21: 7)
- "Partisan Alignments and the Politics of Scarcity,", 1980? (Box-folder 22: 1)
  Includes typescript rough drafts and galley proof
- Code references for tax exemption story, undated (Box-folder 22: 2)
- Article on money and Maryland politics, 1972, and "Indeed Questionable: Do I.Q. Measurements Justify Intellectual Conservatism?" co-authored with Karl W. Deutsch (Box-folder 22: 3-4)
  Typescript drafts
- Washington Post, 1988
  - January - April (Box-folder 22: 5-8)
  - July - November (Box-folder 22: 9-13)
- Book tour schedule, 1991 (Box-folder 22: 14)
- Letter from the Washington Monthly to Thomas Edsall regarding his article, "Money and Politics in Maryland,", 1973 summer (Box 22)
  Includes some drawings by children
- Review of The Reasoning Voter: Communication and Persuasion in Presidential Campaigns, Samuel L. Popkin; Public Opinion in America: Moods, Cycles, and Swings, James Stimsom; and The End of Realignment? Interpreting American Electoral Eras, edited by Byron E. Shafer, 1992 (Box 22)
  Includes typescript and galley proof
- "The Melting Pot Myth Meets Reality: Racism and American Life," lecture, 1991-1992, National Colloquium seminars, 1992 November 13 (Box 22)
  Program only
- Letter from Thomas Edsall to Harriet Morris, Ohio Wesleyan University, Ohio, 1991 September 5 (Box 22)
- "The Problem with Politics," remarks, Mondale Policy Forum, 1991 October (Box 22)
  Letter from Geri Joseph to Thomas Edsall and schedule
- Articles for the Washington Post, 1988-1990 (Box 22)
- Random--Business correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 23: 1)
- VDT reference manual, undated (Box-folder 23: 2)
- Poll-- The Sun, undated (Box-folder 23: 3)
- Facts on race track bill, undated (Box-folder 23: 4)
- Copies of editorials, Baltimore Afro-American, 1972 February 12 (Box-folder 23: 5)
- Journalism memorabilia, 1972 (Box-folder 23: 6)
- Dissent, 1980 (Box-folder 23: 7)
  Includes printed and typescript articles and letters
- Press release from the United States Attorney for the District of Maryland, 1975 November 24; notes; list of contributors, undated; Marvin Mandel--Grand Jury indictment, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 23: 8)
  clippings
- Copies of the Sun, 1974 April 25 and the Washington Post, 1975 June 6 (Box 23)
- Marvin Mandel, 1975 (Box-folder 24: 1)
- Michael Dukakis materials, 1988 (Box-folder 24: 2)
  Includes articles, correspondence, notes, printed matter, and typescript chapters of a book
- Democratic National Committee chair fight, 1989 January 1 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  Includes brochure, clippings, computer printouts, list of members, notes, press release, printed matter, and schedule
- Article on Zbigniew Brzezinski and Sally Quinn, Washington Post, 1979 December 19-21 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  Clipping
- "A New Day for HHC?" Michael C. D. Macdonald, Voice, 1979 August 13 (Box-folder 25: 2)
- "A Faith Fights Russians," Richard Ben Cramer, Boston Globe, 1980 February (Box-folder 25: 3)
- "The Next Assembly Speaker," Cynthia Willett, California Journal, 1979 November (Box-folder 25: 4)
  Printed copy. Includes a clipping on Howard L. Berman, undated
- Articles by Stanley Plastrik, undated (Box-folder 25: 5)
  Photocopies
- D'Alesandro, undated (Box-folder 25: 6)
  Typescript fragments
- Minnesota Farm--Labor. (Box-folder 25: 7)
  Includes correspondence and copies of printed articles, 1918, and clippings, 1982
- Richard H. Chused-—Articles, 1979 (Box-folder 25: 8)
  Printed copies
- Friends in news, such as Benjamin Bradlee, executive editor, Washington Post; Jim and Annie Chapman, Massachusetts; and Jerome and Carol Halberstadt, Newtonville, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 25: 9)
- "Big Wampum for a Legal Tribe," Stuart Taylor, Jr., New York Times, 1981 May 31 (Box-folder 25: 10)
- Barbara Mikulski, Sun, 1981 (Box-folder 25: 11)
- Robert Melson--"Against the Wall,", undated (Box-folder 25: 12)
  Includes "Stealing Books: Resisting in the Fifties," 1972, and a letter from Robert Melson to Karl W. Deutsch, 1977 April 28
- Review by David Guy of Joyride by Gordon Chaplin, Book World, 1982 September 26 (Box-folder 25: 13)
- "The Story of the Pauline Fathers," William Schmick, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 25: 14)
  Includes clippings, newspaper articles, printed copy, and magazine
- "The Unending Agony of Northern Ireland," Sun, 1979 April 1 (Box-folder 25: 15)
  Clipping. Includes letters to Mrs. Thomas Edsall and 2 postcards
- Atlantic '91 (Box-folder 26: 1)
- Mike Barone, 1990 (Box-folder 26: 2)
  Uncorrected page proofs of his forthcoming book, Our Country: The Shaping of America from Roosevelt to Reagan
- Letter from Jackson Hole, 1989 (Box-folder 26: 3)
- "Resolving the Contradictions of Modernity and Modernism," part 2, undated (Box-folder 26: 4)
- Thomas Edsall--Biographical note (Box-folder 26: 5)
- Book party ideas, undated (Box-folder 26: 6)
- David W. Brady--Paper, undated (Box-folder 26: 7)
- Bill Bradley, 1986 (Box-folder 26: 8)
- Brockway--Tax, undated (Box-folder 26: 9)
  Discussion of relationship between politics and tax policy
- Brookings Institution, 1991 (Box-folder 26: 10)
  Letter to Thomas Edsall
- Chain Reaction--Xerox tables for chapter 11, undated (Box-folder 26: 11)
- Merle Black--Writings, 1978-1990 (Box-folder 26: 12)
- Sidney Blumenthal--Writings, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 26: 13)
  Typescript. Includes clippings
- Speech on Chain, Brookings Institution, 1991 (Box-folder 26: 14)
- Adam Clyme--Letter to Thomas Edsall, 1990 April 2 (Box-folder 26: 15)
- Column idea, 1986 (Box-folder 26: 16)
  Typescript, handwritten notes, and clippings
- Louis R. Conte, 1990 (Box-folder 26: 17)
  Includes clippings, a letter, and medical bills
- Letter from Ernesto Cortes, Jr., 1991 (Box-folder 26: 18)
- Stanley Crouch--Second thoughts tape, 1990 May (Box-folder 26: 19)
  Includes a mini sound cassette
- Chandler Davidson-–Letter to Thomas Edsall, 1989 (Box-folder 26: 20)
- Benjamin de Mott, 1990 (Box-folder 26: 21)
- Bob Dowling, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 26: 22)
  Clippings, magazines, and printed matter
- Steven P. Erie, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 26: 23)
  Includes articles, notes, printed matter, letters, and memoranda
- Curtis B. Gans, 1989 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  Article and a letter to Thomas Edsall
- Gary Hart, 1987 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  Clippings and notes
- Andrew Hacker-–Articles, New York Review, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 27: 3)
- Hendrik Hertzberg-–Article, New Republic, 1990 September 3 (Box-folder 27: 4)
- Stephen Rice–-Letter, 1989 May 31 (Box-folder 27: 5)
- Godfrey Hodgson–-Letters from Thomas Edsall, 1988-1991; "The Democratic Party: 1964-1990," article by Thomas Edsall for Facts on File, Inc., 1991 January 15 (Box-folder 27: 6)
  biographical note of Thomas Edsall; and U.S. handbook
- Interview-–GOP book, 1989 (Box-folder 27: 7)
- Speech, post-campaign symposium, organized by Kathleen Jamieson, Austin, Texas, 1988 December (Box-folder 27: 8)
- Randall L. Kennedy--Articles, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 27: 9)
- Joe Klein-—Article, New Republic, 1989 (Box-folder 27: 10)
- Robert Kuttner, New Republic, 1990 April 2 (Box-folder 27: 11)
- Review of John Kenneth White, "The New Politics of Old Values," by Christopher Lasch, New York Review, 1988 July 21 (Box-folder 27: 12)
- Christopher Barker--Article, 1991 February (Box-folder 27: 13)
- Frank Levy and Richard C. Michel--Article, 1990 February (Box-folder 27: 14)
- Seymour Martin Lipset--Articles, 1972-1987 (Box-folder 27: 15)
  Printed copies and clippings
- Glenn Loury--Articles, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 27: 16)
  Printed copies. Includes biographical information
- Bob McIntyre--Citizens for Tax Justice, 1987 (Box-folder 27: 17)
  Brochure only
- Lawrence M. Mea-—Articles, 1990 (Box-folder 27: 18)
  Includes a memorandum and clippings
- Arthur H. Miller--Conference paper, 1989 (Box-folder 27: 19)
- J. Merrill Shanks and Warren Miller, conference paper, 1985 (Box-folder 27: 20)
- Kevin Murphy--Article, 1990 (Box-folder 27: 21)
- Thomas Edsall--Articles, The New Republic, 1990; and review of Kevin Phillips, "Rich and Poor,", 1990 July 1 (Box-folder 28: 1)
- Gary Orfield--Articles, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 28: 2)
- Letter, 1990, from Lisa M. Dellwo to Thomas Edsall regarding Black Votes Count: Political Empowerment in Mississippi after 1865 by Frank Parker (Box-folder 28: 3)
- Gary Peller--Typescript chapter from "Liberalism, Black Nationalism, and Jews,", 1990? (Box-folder 28: 4)
- John R. Petrocik, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 29: 5)
  Typescript papers and copy of printed article
- Kevin Phillips-—Articles, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 29: 6)
- GOP book--Planmaster, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 28: 7)
- Gerald M. Pomper--Articles, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 28: 8)
  Includes bibliography for "Chain Reaction" by Thomas Edsall, 1991
- Joel Rogers--Correspondence with Thomas Edsall, 1987 (Box-folder 28: 9)
- Isabel V. Sawhill and Erol R. Ricketts papers, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 28: 10)
- Schmooz list, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 28: 11)
  Includes list of names, consultant directory, notes, and a letter from Peter Seidman to Thomas Edsall
- Letter from David O. Sears to Thomas Edsall, 1990 (Box-folder 28: 12)
- "The American Power Structure: Liberty and Justice for All?" Second Annual Occidental Public Affairs Conference (OPAC), Los Angeles, California, 1991 February 7-9 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  Includes a letter, 1990 July 9, from Jennifer M. Roth extending to Thomas Edsall an invitation to participate. Also includes copy of airline ticket and a letter from Thomas Edsall to Derek Shearer, 1988 November 7
- Fred Siegel--Article, 1991 May 12 (Box-folder 29: 2)
  Printed copy. Includes a letter from him to Thomas and Mary Edsall, 1991 May 14
- Sociologists--American Sociological Association on the issue of observing the twentieth anniversary of the assassination of Martin Luther King, Jr., 1988 March 20 (Box-folder 29: 3)
  Includes photocopy of a printed article by Julie Johnson, 1989 July 28
- Harold W. Stanley--Book review and articles, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 29: 4)
  Typescript and printed copies. Includes articles by others
- Stuart Taylor-—Article, 1989 July (Box-folder 29: 5)
- Lester C. Thurow, 1990 (Box-folder 29: 6)
- Review by Anna Quindlen of Laurence H. Tribe, "Abortion: The Clash of Absolutes,", 1990 June 3 (Box-folder 29: 7)
- William Brennan-—Article by Thomas Edsall, 1990 July 27 (Box-folder 29: 8)
- Media Guide, evaluation of the writings of Thomas Edsall and others, undated (Box-folder 29: 9)
  Photocopy of a printed article
- John Kenneth White--Article, 1989 winter (Box-folder 29: 10)
  Typescript. Includes letters to Thomas Edsall, 1988 October 28 and December 14
- Review of James Q. Wilson, "The Shaping of America from Roosevelt to Reagan" by Michael Barone, New Republic, 1990 July 2, 1988 (Box-folder 29: 11)
- Corporate profits, 1987 (Box-folder 29: 12)
- Cultural policy, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 29: 13)
- Courts, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 29: 14)
- De-institutionalized, 1990 (Box-folder 29: 15)
  Clippings. Includes articles by others on the subject of mental disability, Rutgers Law Review, winter/spring 1987. Printed copies
- Demographics, undated (Box-folder 29: 16)
- Michael K. Deaver, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 29: 17)
  Includes articles by Thomas Edsall, printed matter, press release, registration statements, report, and other related materials
- Blacks, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 29: 18)
  Includes clippings and printed matter, conference paper, and printed articles from the American Journal of Political Science
- Central Intelligence Agency, 1986 March (Box-folder 30: 1)
- Churches, 1990 January (Box-folder 30: 2)
- Coalition politics, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 30: 3)
- Consultants, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 30: 4)
  Includes article by Thomas Edsall, clippings, and consultant directory
- Black success, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 30: 5)
  Includes clippings, memorandum, and reports
- Lee Atwater, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 30: 6-9)
  Includes articles by Thomas Edsall, clippings and printed matter, letters, list of members in various committees of the Republican Party by state, presidential campaign, 1981-1984, and post-election environmental records
- Lee Atwater, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 31: 1)
- Affirmative action, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 31: 2-5)
  Includes articles, clippings and printed matter, letters, memoranda, papers written on the subject, press releases, and reports
- American Indian, 1990 (Box-folder 31: 6)
- Bill Drayton-—Ashoka Innovators for the Public, 1991 (Box-folder 31: 7)
  Includes a letter to Thomas Edsall, memorandum, and personnel records
- England, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 31: 8)
  Clippings and printed matter
- Affirmative action, 1968-1990 (Box-folder 32: 1-4)
  Includes articles, clippings and printed matter, memoranda, statistical data, and reports
- Helen Epstein, 1991 (Box-folder 32: 5)
  Typescript chapters of a book?
- Europe, Australia, and New Zealand, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 32: 6)
- Fan mail, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 32: 7)
  Congratulatory letters to Thomas and Mary Edsall
- Review of Gary Gerstle and Steve Fraser, editors, "Missed Opportunities: The Rise and Fall of the New Deal Order" by Thomas Edsall, Progressive, 1989 June (Box-folder 32: 8)
- Correspondence with John Green, 1989 (Box-folder 32: 9)
- Burt Hoffman, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 32: 10)
  Correspondence and photocopy of an article about Ronald Reagan
- Coria Holland, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 33: 1)
  Includes letters to Thomas Edsall, biographical information, and photocopies of articles written by Ms. Holland
- The American Prospect, undated (Box-folder 33: 2)
- Immigration
  - Background materials, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 33: 3-4)
  - Information concerning the ties between U.S. English and immigration restrictionist organizations, 1986-1990, and a report, "Population and Labor Force of New York: 1990-2050," by Leon F. Bouvier and Vernon M. Briggs, Jr., 1988 (Box-folder 33: 5)
  - Clippings, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 33: 6)
  - Miscellany, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 33: 7)
- GOP--Analysis, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 33: 8)
- Norman Birnbaum, 1988 (Box-folder 33: 9)
- Typescript fragment, 1990, possibly to be used as a flap/ jacket copy for "Chain Reaction: Race, Rights, Reform, and Taxes" by Thomas Edsall (Box-folder 33: 10)
- Lynne P. Brown, 1988 (Box-folder 33: 11)
  Letter to Thomas Edsall, 1988 July 27
- David R. Cameron-—Conference papers to be presented at University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1981 March, and at Stanford University, 1982 October (Box-folder 33: 12)
- Lincoln Kaplan, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  Typescript and photocopy of articles
- Celia Morris-—Letter to Mary Edsall, 1990 (Box-folder 34: 2)
- Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  Includes correspondence with Donald McDonald and brochures
- Clippings about Thomas Edsall, 1986 (Box-folder 34: 4)
- Photocopy of an article by Richard A. Cloward and Frances Fox Piven, 1966 (Box-folder 34: 5)
- Dissent
  - Review of Steven P. Erie, Rainbow's End, Irish-Americans and the Dilemmas of Urban Machine Politics, 1840-1985, 1989 (Box-folder 34: 6)
    Typescript. Also includes correspondence with Irvin Howe and Emanuel Geltman, 1986-1987. Folder is incorrectly labeled as 1986 October
  - Review of David Vogel, Fluctuating Fortunes: The Political Power of Business in America, 1990 January 14 (Box-folder 34: 7)
    Typescript. Includes correspondence with Irving Howe, 1987-1990
  - Thomas Edsall's letter to Irving Howe, 1989 January (Box-folder 34: 8)
    The folder is incorrectly labeled as 1989 February
  - "Business in American Politics," review of David Vogel, Fluctuating Fortunes: The Political Power of Business in America. (Box-folder 34: 9)
    Photocopy. Includes a letter to Irving Howe, 1990 January
- Correspondence with Carl F. Pinkele, Director, National Colloquium, Ohio Wesleyan, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 34: 10)
  Includes typescript version of Thomas Edsall's speech, 1986 November, and issues of The Civic Arts Review, 1988 summer
- Peter E. Quint, 1990 (Box-folder 34: 11)
  Photocopy of an article in the Baltimore Sun
- Letter from Deborah A. Verstegen, 1989 June 26, requesting an article for a proposed book, "Spheres of Justice in American Schools" (Box-folder 34: 12)
- Letters from the Robbins Office, Inc., 1989-1991 (Box-folder 34: 13)
  Includes royalty statements
- Speech on the role of party-in-government, Committee for Party Renewal Conference, Eagleton Institute, Rutgers University, New Jersey, 1987 January (Box-folder 34: 14)
  Includes typescript drafts, final speeches, related correspondence, and expense reports
- Letter from Michael Schudson, University of California, San Diego, 1991 March 5, and fragment of an article on "Myth,", 1992 January (Box-folder 34: 15)
- Articles about John Silber, 1974-1990 (Box-folder 34: 16)
  Includes clippings, printed matter, and handwritten notes
- Introduction to "Power and Money," Washington Monthly, 1988 April 3 version (Box-folder 34: 17)
  Typescript. Includes correspondence with Charles Peters, 1988, and a list of people invited to the book party, 1988 June
- Richard Gephardt's comments about American businesses, Washington Times, 1988 January 29 (Box-folder 34: 18)
  Clippings. Includes Gephardt's ad scripts on different subjects
- Correspondence with Lewis H. Lapham, Harper's Magazine, 1988 March (Box-folder 34: 19)
- Bob Healy-—Letter to Helen?, 1991 (Box-folder 34: 20)
- Frederic B. Hill, 1992 (Box-folder 34: 21)
  Includes letter to Thomas Edsall; biographical information; list of policy planning exercises and programs of the Center for the Study of Foreign Affairs, Foreign Service Institute, Department of State; and report on the Foreign Service in 2001, School of Foreign Service, Georgetown University
- Interviews by Thomas Edsall, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 34: 22)
- Invitational letters from Gary Miller to be the keynote speaker, Winning the National Election Conference, Sacramento, California, 1988 January 23, and from Susan Goodwin to deliver a lecture, Washington School, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 34: 23)
- Speech, Washington Semester Program, American University, 1989 October 4 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  Includes handwritten notes, letters of appreciation, 1989-1990, and a letter of invitation to speak again, 1990 February 12
- John B. Judis-—Article, Nation, 1983 May 21 (Box-folder 35: 2)
  Printed copy. Includes a letter to Thomas Edsall, 1990 July 15
- Mark A. R. Kleiman-—Plan for the contents of a book, undated (Box-folder 35: 3)
- A thank you letter, 1992 February 15, from Daryl Knight for the gift of a check for $400.00 (Box-folder 35: 4)
- "Trends in Whites' Explanation of the Black-White Gap in Socio-economic Status, 1977-1989," article by James R. Kluegel, 1990 (Box-folder 35: 5)
- Nelson Lichtenstein-—Articles, one (with Robert Korstad), 1988 (Box-folder 35: 6)
- Federal Election Commission (FEC) Final Report on Financial Activity (1987-1988), 1989 September (Box-folder 35: 7)
- Articles, New York Times, 1989 (Box-folder 35: 8)
- "Politics and Money," speech, American Culture's Conference on the Media and the Electoral Process, Northwestern University, 1988 May 20-21 (Box-folder 35: 9)
  Typescript and related correspondence
- Mitchell Orenstein, 1990 (Box-folder 35: 10-11)
  Includes biographical information, articles, law school essay, letters, and notes
- Clips book-—Jacket photo, 4 contact sheets, and negatives, 1987 (Box-folder 35: 12)
- The Atlantic Monthly, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 35: 13)
  Includes letters of appreciation and requests for permission to include materials
- Thomas Edsall's quote for Why Americans Don't Vote by Frances Fox Piven and Richard A. Cloward, 1988 February 6 (Box-folder 35: 14)
  Includes correspondence with Gerald Howard, 1990, and letter from Naomi Schneider, 1989
- Boston Globe, 1989 (Box-folder 35: 15)
- David S. Broder, 1989 (Box-folder 35: 16)
- Correspondence, 1990 (Box-folder 35: 17)
- Dissent, 1989 (Box-folder 35: 18)
  Consists of a letter to the editor from Irving Howe
- Pete du Pont-—Remarks, Chicago, Illinois, 1986 April 26 (Box-folder 35: 19)
  Typescript. Includes a press release
- Bob Dole, 1970-1987 (Box-folder 36: 1-3)
  Includes articles, clippings, printed matter, interview, itinerary, list of appointments, notebook, Senate public financial disclosure report, and speech to receive the Republican Party's nomination to the office of the President of the United States
- Speech on Reagan legacy, George Washington University, 1989 (Box-folder 36: 4)
  Typescript. Includes letters to Thomas Edsall, 1988-1989
- Liberal problems, 1986 (Box-folder 36: 5)
- Market economics, 1990 (Box-folder 36: 6)
- "Lobbies," Paul Taylor's series, 1983 (Box-folder 36: 7)
  Clippings and other related materials including a letter to Thomas Edsall and an article by him, 1987-1989
- Liberal attacks, 1986 (Box-folder 36: 8)
- Liberal curb, 1990 (Box-folder 36: 9)
- Legal Services Corporation (LSC), 1989-1990 (Box-folder 36: 10)
  Includes articles, background information, fact sheet, clippings, and printed materials
- Political Action Committee (PAC), 1984-1985 (Box-folder 36: 11)
  Includes brochure, letter, printed matter, and press releases
- Committee on Ways and Means-—Letter from Wendell Primus, 1989 (Box-folder 36: 12)
- Labor Unions, 1984 (Box-folder 36: 13)
  Clippings, 1985-1990
- Productivity, 1986 (Box-folder 36: 14)
- Polls II, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 37: 1-5)
  Includes articles, charts, clippings, printed matter, election and statistical data, reports, and survey
- The Public Interest, undated (Box-folder 37: 6)
  Lists of names and documents
- Privatization, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 37: 7)
- Prejudice--Paper by Myron Rothbart and Oliver P. John, 1985 (Box-folder 37: 8)
- Prediction?, 1989 (Box-folder 37: 9)
- Negative campaigning 1988, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 37: 10)
  Includes articles, clippings, and fliers
- Richard Nixon, 1973 (Box-folder 37: 11)
  Printed copy of oath of office and second inaugural address
- Oil and GOP--Notes, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 37: 12)
  Includes clippings and printed matter
- Names, 1985 December 12 (Box-folder 37: 13)
  Thomas Edsall's list of interviewees for GOP book
- Mayors, 1990 (Box-folder 37: 14)
- Moonies-—Reverand Sun Myung Moon, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 37: 15)
  Articles, including one by Thomas Edsall, and clippings
- Entrepreneurs, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 37: 16)
- John "Terry" Dolan, 1987 (Box-folder 37: 17)
- Money I, 1979-1990 (Box-folder 38: 1-3)
  Includes articles, clippings, conference papers, journal, press release, remarks, reports, and study
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), 1990 (Box-folder 38: 4)
  Clippings and report
- Labor II, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 38: 5)
  Clippings, printed matter, press release, and remarks
- Chrysler, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 38: 6)
  Articles, clippings, and other printed matter
- General Motors (GM), 1977-1986 (Box-folder 38: 7)
- Ford, 1977-1990 (Box-folder 38: 8)